Xavier University Schedule of Classes collection
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Schedule of Classes collection
1959-2014
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)
2.5 linear feet (5 boxes)
This is a collection of class schedules from the various academic programs at Xavier University. Schedules are found for the Undergraduate Colleges, the Center for Adult and Part-Time Students (formerly known as the College of Continuing Education), Weekend Degree Program, the Graduate School, the Master of Business Administration Program, Summer Sessions, and Graduate and Undergraduate Day and Evening classes.
XUA-49
History of Xavier University Schedule of Classes collection
This collection entails those Xavier University Schedule of Classes held by Xavier University Archives.The earliest issue in this collection dates from 1959. This archival collection, though substantial, is not complete.
From at least 1974 to 1989, four different schedules of classes were published each semester for the various academic divisions of the University. All undergraduate courses, day and evening, appeared in one publication produced by the Office of the Registrar. The College of Continuing Education, later called the Center for Adult and Part-Time Students, published its own Schedule of Classes, though its courses were also listed in the Registrar's brochure. The Graduate School (Programs) published its bulletin of courses. Similarly, the Master of Business Program had its own printed schedule.
However, beginning with the Fall Semester 1989, just one Schedule of Classes was published each semester in a newspaper format for all courses (graduate, undergraduate, day and evening). There was one exception: courses in the Weekend Program, which began in 1995, were usually not included in this Schedule of Classes, but were published separately.
Summer courses were always published in a separate bulletin which included all summer classes, graduate, undergraduate, day and evening.
Beginning the the Fall of 2009, the Semester Schedule of Classes no longer appeared in printed form. It was available only online. However, the Summer Sessions continued to publish its class schedule in a paper format as in the past.
Scope and Content
This is a collection of the various schedule of classes published by the academic divisions of Xavier University.
Statement of Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
1. Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening: Schedule of Classes, 1989-2009
2. Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 1959-2014
3. Undergraduate Colleges (Day and Evening): Schedule of Classes, 1974-1989
4. College of Continuing Education: Schedule of Classes, 1975-1994
5. Weekend Degree Program: Schedule of Classes, 1995-2008
6. Graduate School: Schedule of Classes, 1977-1989
7. Master of Business Administration Program: Schedule, 1977-1989
Separated Material
These various schedules have been digitized and are found on the archive's digital storage drive. Please contact the archives staff.
Related Material
Xavier University course catalogs from 1841 to the present are also found in the archive's collections, both in hard copy and digital formats. Please contact the archives staff.
Accruals
Some additions can be expected to this collection.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Schedules, School--Ohio; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Curricula--Catalogs
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Office of the Registrar; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Graduate School; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Master of Business Administration Program; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Center for Adult and Part-Time Education; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Weekend Degree Program
Detailed Description of The Collection
- 1. Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening: Schedule of Classes, 1989-2009
  - Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening Schedule of Classes, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening: Schedule of Classes, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening: Schedule of Classes, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening: Schedule of Classes, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening Schedule of Classes, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening Schedule of Classes, 2007-2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate and Graduate, Day and Evening For the Record (Registrar Newsletter), 1997-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 2. Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 1959-2014
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 1967-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 1978-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 1995-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 2002-2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 2008-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Summer Sessions: Catalogs and Schedule of Classes, 2011-2014 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 3. Undergraduate Colleges (Day and Evening): Schedule of Classes, 1974-1989
  - Undergraduate Colleges (Day and Evening): Schedule of Classes, 1974-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate Colleges (Day and Evening): Schedule of Classes, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate Colleges (Day and Evening): Schedule of Classes, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- 4. Center for Adult and Part-Time Students (College of Continuing Education), 1975-1994
  - Center for Adult and Part-Time Students (College of Continuing Education): Schedule of Classes, 1975-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- 5. Weekend Degree Program: Schedule of Classes, 1995-2008
  - Weekend Degree Program: Schedules, 1995-2008 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- 6. Graduate School: Schedule of Classes, 1977-1989
  - Graduate School: Schedule of Classes, 1977-1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- 7. Master of Business Administration Program, 1977-1989
  - Master of Business Administration Program: Schedules, 1977-1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)